Deno一种全新的编写服务器端JavaScript的方式
Deno a brand new way to write server-side JavaScript
它解决了许多nodejs的问题，他们甚至是同一个家伙创建的
it solves many of the same problems as Nodejs and was even created by the same guy
Deno使用v8 JavaScript引擎
like node it uses the v8 JavaScript engine under the hood
但其余部分是Rust和Typescript开发的
but the rest of the runtime is implemented in rust and typescript
我们探索Deno的旅程始于一个TypeScript文件
our journey into Deno land begins in a single TypeScript file
在这个文件中 我们可以访问运行时的所有类型
in this file we have access to all the types in the
这意味着我们可以编写强类型代码
runtime which means we can write strongly typed code
并在IDE中查看文档和使用intellisense 无需配置
and get documentation and intellisense directly in the IDE without ever needing to touch a TS config file.
运行时的功能可以从Deno的命名空间中得到
the features in the runtime can be accessed from this Deno namespace
让我们打印一下当前工作目录
let's console.log the current working directory of the filesystem
可以从命令行运行脚本
we can execute our script with Deno run from the command line
但是你会注意到出错，这是因为默认情况下Deno安全的，
but you'll notice the throws an error and that's because Deno is secure by default
开发人员需要授予运行时执行不同操作的权限
you the developer need to give permission to perform different actions in the runtime
这种情况 我们可以使用allow read标志来允许此操作
in this case we can use the allow read flag to allow this operation
安全性很棒，但是我最喜欢的是 Deno的异步都是基于Promise的
security is great but my favorite thing is how everything asynchronous is promise based
我们可以使用fetch API发出网络请求，就像在浏览器中一样
we can make a network request using the fetch API just like we would in the browser
并且因为它支持顶层的await，我们甚至不需要async函数
and because it supports top-level wait we don't even need an async function
我们可以决议promise，而无需任何模版代码
here we can start resolving promises without any extra
Deno尝试使你的代码和浏览器兼容
boilerplate code Deno attempts to make your code as browser compatible as possible
它包含一个window对象 你可以监听它的生命周期事件
it contains a window object with lifecycle events that you can listen to
开发人员可以更轻松地编写在服务器和浏览器中可中断的代码
allowing developers to more easily write code that can interrupt between browsers and servers
更不用说它也可以执行Web Assembly二进制文件
not to mention it can also execute web assembly binaries
Deno中不支持一件事是NPM
but one thing that won't work in Deno are your NPM packages instead
取而代之 你使用模块语法通过url来引用模块
you import packages using the module yes module syntax with remote modules being referenced by their URL
当你首次运行时
when you run your script for the first time it will
在本地下载此代码并缓存 没有package.json 可以通过url引用任何你想要的代码
download this code locally and cache it there's no package JSON and code can be
非常类似于浏览器的引用文件的方式
referenced from any URL very similar to how things work in the browser
Deno提供了一组标准模块来解决常见的用例
Deno provides a set of standard modules to solve common use cases for example we
例如我们可以从http模块导入服务，我们可以使用它来创建服务器
can import serve from the HTTP module we can use it to create a server that's
服务器被视为异步可迭代，然后我们可以等待每个请求，
treated as an async iterable we can then await every request from the server and
然后做出响应，这是服务器端的绝佳起点
respond to it accordingly and that's an awesome starting point for a server-side JavaScript app now
Deno刚刚发布了1.0版本，所以如果你开始
Deno 1.0 just hit release candidate 1 so if you start
如果现在开始使用，就算早期用户
using it today consider yourself an early adopter do
你认为Deno是服务器端JavaScript的未来吗 写下评论
you think Deno is the future of server-side JavaScript?  the comments below
感谢你的观看 别忘了点赞 下集再见
thanks for watching hit the like button and I will see you in next one